Derek Murray

♦ Phone: (443) 882-2225 ♦ Email: Derekmurray928@gmail.com ♦ LinkedIn: <u>Derek Murray</u> ♦ Github: <u>Derekm28</u>

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer skilled in JavaScript, Python, SQL, Git/terminal, React, Express and Node.JS. Over 10 years experience building companies and teams in several industries as a manager and entrepreneur. Looking to continue growing as a Software Engineer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS **Front End:** React, Bootstrap, JavaScript, AJAX/JSON

Back End: NodeJS, ExpressJS, Python, Flask, REST, PostgreSQL **Platforms and Services:** Google Analytics, Facebook Ads Manager

Development and Deployment: Git, GitHub, Heroku

PROJECTS

Forepast

- Historic weather app that retrieves historical weather data for locations around the world
- Saves searched results to a database
- Tools: Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, Metaweather API

Warbler

- Twitter clone capable of log in, posting tweets and following fake users generated from an API
- Tools: Python, Flask, PostgreSQL

Heaat

- Tennis shoe release date site that pulls data from API and displays information on an item card
- Able to create a user account that saves encrypted log-in information to a database.
- Tools: React, Express, Node.Js, PostgreSQL

EXPERIENCE

Charm City Knockerball | Managing Partner | Baltimore, MD

Jan. 2016 - 2020

- Established customer-centric culture of communication, collaboration, and accountability, resulting in a 4.8 out of 5 Google review score
- Collected and analyzed sales performance and market trends to better serve existing customer base and identify growth opportunities
- Orchestrated strategic Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and TikTok marketing campaigns, increasing brand awareness and revenue over 300% within two years

Murray's Home Detailing | Founder & CEO | Baltimore, MD

May 2009 – June 2016

- Increased sales year-over-year through targeted marketing campaigns and referrals, generating 6-figure sales and serving 500+ residential and commercial clients
- Hired, trained, and supervised technicians, ensuring consistent service quality

Primerica Financial Services | Financial Analyst | Baltimore, MD

Feb. 2005 – Apr. 2009

- Collaborated with executives to identify and improve training needs
- Produced financial reports evaluating completed projects, identifying current trends, and evaluating variances and providing financial guidance
- Counseled clients one-on-one, recommending customized, data-informed investment strategies

EDUCATION

Springboard | Software Engineering Fellow | Baltimore, MD

May 2020 – July 2021

- Designed a full stack application using Python, Flask and PostgreSQL that generates historical weather data from the MetaWeather API for locations around the world
- Created interactive front-end web applications with React, Javascript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap
- Developed server-side applications and API's with NodeJS, Python and Flask
- Built applications integrated with databases using PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Python, Flask

Anne Arundel Community College | Arnold, MD

• Associate of Applied Science & Business Management